Justin Le Tourneau

Address Columbia, MO 65201 Phone (636) 697-2120

Email justin.letourn@gmail.com

Website
justin-letourneau.dev

Motivated Programmer and System Administrator with 8 years of experience designing, writing and deploying software for a variety of systems and use cases. Committed to improving user experiences through interface usability and functionality. Seeking a position that values learning, critical thinking and autonomy.

Skills and Proficiencies

Programming

• <u>Development Languages:</u>

Ruby, Python, Javascript, C++, Java, Perl, PHP, Shell Scripting

o Web Front-End:

Vue.js, React.js, Vuex, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, Sass, Webpack, etc

o Web Back-End:

Node.js, Ruby on Rails, PHP, ColdFusion, Groovy, Django

O Web Services:

Socket.io, REST, SOAP, GraphQL, Sequelize, web tokens, etc.

- <u>Mobile</u>: Java (currently experimenting with Flutter and React Native)
- <u>Desktop:</u> C++ in Microsoft WinForms and Qt
- Search Engines: Solr, Lucene and Elasticsearch
- Databases:
- o SQL Postgresql, SQLite, MySQL
- o NoSQL MongoDB, ArangoDB, Neo4j
- Interface design and mockup: Mockflow and Adobe XD
- Version Control: Git

Administration

Management:

CentOS, Redhat and Debian servers and virtual machines

• Web Servers:

Nginx, Apache, Tomcat

- <u>Database administration and optimization:</u> PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- <u>Hardware:</u> Installed, configured and maintained servers, switches and storage
- <u>Software:</u> Compile, install, monitor performance and manage system resources.
- <u>Automation:</u> deploying virtual machines, archiving backups, general administration tasks, etc.
- Working with stakeholders to address needs for storage, setup, and provisioning. Implement standards for data storage and archiving.

Work History

Research Analyst - Linux Administrator, 2016 to Current

University Of Missouri - Columbia, Missouri

- Created a data portal, education and various other research sites for National Science Foundation grant project
 - o Javascript, Django, Groovy, PHP, Drupal, Node.js, Vue.js, React.js
- Managed, archived and maintained all research data for Missouri EPSCoR state wide grant project
- Write and maintain bioinformatics research software for genome assembly browsers and genomic data mining
- Collaborate with faculty, postdocs and students to solve technical problems and contribute to research projects.
 - o Pipelines and projects: Ruby, Python, C++, Shell, Javascript, R
- Contributed software for research papers on genetic tools, bioinformatics and educational software
 Maintain 10 high-performance research servers and many (20 or so) kvm / vmware virtual machines
- Installed and managed software: WARF, R, Matlab, genetic pipelines, SMRTLink, etc.

Quetza Software CTO, 2018 to Current

Quetza Software LLC - Columbia, Missouri

- Founded software company for developing agricultural educational products for academic and industry use
- Single full-stack developer for SeeGenetics and SeeBeefGenetics web applications. Created applications, authentication service, key / licensing software, educator portal and AI game companion. Designed both game and key features.
 - Vue.js, Vuex, Bulma, oAuth, Express.js, Sequelize, Postgresql

Programmer Analyst, 2012 to 2016

University Of Missouri – Columbia, Missouri

- Built specialty web applications for financial officers and controllers
- Wrote software to interface with credit card companies and the campus bookstore
- Re-wrote custom, legacy software and updated for modern use and maintenance
- $\bullet \quad \hbox{Created javascript framework for quickly building and deploying financial reports} \\$

Freelance Developer, 2006 to 2012

Self Employed - St. Louis, Missouri

- Wrote software and web applications for various clients in the St. Louis area, for example:
 - o C. Rallo Meat Company
 - created software (C++) to link scales together for pricing information
 - $\,\blacksquare\,\,$ created mobile apps (Java) for various in-store calculations and pricing
 - o Saint Louis Wrestling Officials Association Scheduling website for Missouri high schools and officials
 - Ruby on Rails, PHP

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Webster University - Webster Groves, MO